<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>"There's always money in the banana stand!" - Articles</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/feeds/articles.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ps2fino.github.io/</id><updated>2019-07-17T16:00:22+02:00</updated><entry><title>How to solve virtual reality’s human perception problem</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/the_conversation_march_2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-17T16:00:22+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2018-03-05:/the_conversation_march_2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote a piece for The Conversation on my work in psychophysics.
You can read the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://theconversation.com/how-to-solve-virtual-realitys-human-perception-problem-92128"&gt;published article here&lt;/a&gt;.
Below is the original unedited draft I wrote for those&amp;nbsp;interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="unedited-article"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unedited&amp;nbsp;Article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of entertainment, virtual reality (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt;) has seen significant uptake in more practical domains.
For example, using &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote a piece for The Conversation on my work in psychophysics.
You can read the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://theconversation.com/how-to-solve-virtual-realitys-human-perception-problem-92128"&gt;published article here&lt;/a&gt;.
Below is the original unedited draft I wrote for those&amp;nbsp;interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="unedited-article"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unedited&amp;nbsp;Article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of entertainment, virtual reality (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt;) has seen significant uptake in more practical domains.
For example, using &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; to piece together parts of a car engine to test out a look and feel before the manufacturing process. Or to try on the latest fashion accessory before you buy.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7T4bdlRDOdk"&gt;Our own recent work&lt;/a&gt; at Bath has applied &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; to exercise; imagine going to the gym to take part in the Tour de France and race against the world’s top&amp;nbsp;cyclists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; has been successful, it is not without its kinks.
Designing an interactive system does not stop at the hardware and software; the human must be factored in too.
Perception is the term for how we take information from the world and build understanding from it.
Our perception of reality is what we base our decisions on, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TVCG.2017.2657138"&gt;mostly determines our sense of presence in an environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how to tackle the problem of designing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; systems that really transport us to new worlds with an acceptable sense of presence?
As the scale of the problem grows, it becomes difficult to quantify the contribution each element of the experience makes to the person&amp;#8217;s sense of presence.
For example, when watching a 360 film in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt;, it is difficult to determine if the on screen animations contribute more or less than the 360 audio technology deployed in the experience.
What we need is a method for studying &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; in a reductionist manner; removing the clutter then adding piece by piece to observe the effect each has in&amp;nbsp;turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One theory blends together computer science and psychology: maximum likelihood estimation explains how we combine the information we receive across all our senses, integrating it together to inform our understanding of the environment.
In its simplest form, it states that we combine sensory information in an optimal fashion; each sense contributes an estimate of the environment but it is&amp;nbsp;noisy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scenario is depicted in the figure below which shows how the estimates from our eyes and ears combine to give an optimal estimate somewhere in the middle.
Note how the blue curve is slimmer than the other two showing decreased variance; the combined estimate takes the best of both worlds.
It is also positioned between the two sensory estimates, showing a compromise of the two.
Finally, note it is taller: this corresponds to a higher likelihood in its&amp;nbsp;estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Pictorial description of maximum likelihood estimation. 2 sensory signals are combined, with result being a signal of less variance, with a mean value in between the sensory signals" src="https://ps2fino.github.io/images/march-2018/mle.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has many applications in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/SIVE.2017.7901607"&gt;Our recent work&lt;/a&gt; has applied this to solving a problem in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; with how people estimate distances.
Imagine using a driving simulator for teaching people how to drive.
If people compress distances in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt;, then using it as a learning environment would be&amp;nbsp;inappropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding how people integrate information from their senses is crucial to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; because it is not solely visual. Maximum Likelihood Estimation is a tool to model how effectively a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; system &lt;em&gt;needs&lt;/em&gt; to render its multisensory environment in order to deliver the desired experience. Understanding perception will lead to more immersive &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; experiences.
It&amp;#8217;s not a matter of separating each signal from the noise; it&amp;#8217;s a matter of taking all signals with the noise to give the most likely&amp;nbsp;result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Articles"></category><category term="article"></category><category term="vr"></category></entry></feed>