<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>"There's always money in the banana stand!" - Papers</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/feeds/papers.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ps2fino.github.io/</id><updated>2025-09-01T13:39:30+02:00</updated><entry><title>New paper at BCS HCI 2025!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/bcs-hci-2025.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-08-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T13:39:30+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2025-08-04:/bcs-hci-2025.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted at BCS HCI 2025!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural Heritage institutions such as Galleries, Libraries, Archives, and Museums are tasked with preserving our history and heritage for future generations while engaging new audiences with an appetite for said engagement to be increasingly digital and interactive. 
To …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted at BCS HCI 2025!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural Heritage institutions such as Galleries, Libraries, Archives, and Museums are tasked with preserving our history and heritage for future generations while engaging new audiences with an appetite for said engagement to be increasingly digital and interactive. 
To explore how advances in natural language processing, particularly large language models (LLMs), may help GLAMs in their mission, we designed a prototype ‘Chattable’ avatar, a 3D high-polygon animated character which visitors can talk to and interact with. 
We report the design of our avatar, and a workshop we conducted with curators and staff from a GLAM institution, to understand the problems, requirements, and opportunities LLMs present in the cultural heritage space. 
We present results from a qualitative analysis of our workshop highlighting themes such as trust, authority, social experience, and location, finding LLMs may be more suited to deployments focused on non-factual data dissemination. 
We conclude with implications for GLAMs and suggestions for future research to realise how best to integrate GenerativeAI like LLMs into the GLAM space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jiang, Z., Qin, Y., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;'Chattable' Avatars: Using LLMs to Power Visitor Engagement with Historical Persons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Proceedings of the BCS Special Interest Group in Human Computer Interaction (BCS HCI) Conference 2025&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://orca.cardiff.ac.uk/id/eprint/180401/1/Chattable-Avatar.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.XXXX/XXXX"&gt;DOI: Pending&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="generativeAI"></category><category term="museums and galleries"></category><category term="LLMs"></category><category term="large language models"></category><category term="workshop"></category></entry><entry><title>New paper at INTERACT 2025!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/interact-2025.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-08-04T12:53:31+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2025-05-01:/interact-2025.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to &lt;a href="https://www.cardiff.ac.uk/people/research-students/view/bamoallem,-razan"&gt;Razan Bamoallem&lt;/a&gt; who has had a paper accepted at INTERACT 2025!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For individuals with MS and dexterity impairments (MSDex), touchscreen interaction can be particularly challenging, as symptoms like finger numbness and impaired motion regulation negatively impact smartphone usability. 
This study investigated the usability and accessibility …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to &lt;a href="https://www.cardiff.ac.uk/people/research-students/view/bamoallem,-razan"&gt;Razan Bamoallem&lt;/a&gt; who has had a paper accepted at INTERACT 2025!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For individuals with MS and dexterity impairments (MSDex), touchscreen interaction can be particularly challenging, as symptoms like finger numbness and impaired motion regulation negatively impact smartphone usability. 
This study investigated the usability and accessibility of a mid-air gesture interaction technique for MS-Dex. 
Touchscreen technologies are ubiquitous, but these individuals often face challenges with touch-based interaction. 
Touchless input methods, like midair gestures, offer a promising alternative for enhancing interaction and communication with touch-based technology. 
We developed an interactive tool (HF-MAI) using hand and finger mid-air gestures for common touchscreen tasks, using the Leap Motion Controller (LMC) for gesture recognition. 
MS-Dex individuals, MS therapists, and a usability and user experience (UX) expert participated in the evaluation. 
We assessed usability, user satisfaction, and accessibility of the HF-MAI system. 
Results indicate HF-MAI is highly usable and accessible; participants performed gestures successfully and reported high satisfaction. 
Notably, pinch, spread, and rotate (two-finger/single-finger) mid-air gestures were performed with faster completion times, contrasting with the difficulty of such gestures on touchscreens. 
The gesture vocabulary, particularly the adaptation to single/two-finger movements, facilitated easier interaction, reducing difficulty for users with limited dexterity. 
This study demonstrates the potential of mid-air gestures using co-created vocabularies to enhance accessibility for individuals with MS, offering a promising alternative to traditional touch-based input. 
This technology can significantly improve their access to touchscreens, enhancing independence and quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bamoallem, R., Loizides, F., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; AlSunaidi, H.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;HF-MAI: Touchless Mid-Air Interaction for Individuals with Dexterity Impairment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
20th IFIP TC13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction (INTERACT) 2025&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.XXXX/XXXX"&gt;DOI:10.XXXX/XXXX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="accessibility"></category></entry><entry><title>New paper accepted in ACM CHI PLAY 2024!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chiplay-2024.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T11:22:05+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2024-09-12:/chiplay-2024.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;ACM CHI PLAY 2024&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VR exergaming is a promising motivational tool to incentivise exercise. 
We present a novel VR exergaming method called social interactive feedforward. 
The player competes with an 'enhanced model' of one of their friends in a real-time VR …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;ACM CHI PLAY 2024&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VR exergaming is a promising motivational tool to incentivise exercise. 
We present a novel VR exergaming method called social interactive feedforward. 
The player competes with an 'enhanced model' of one of their friends in a real-time VR environment, showing improved performance levels in a way the player can relate to. 
Social interactive feedforward was tested in a cycling-based VR exergame and players competed with enhanced models of themselves, their friend, and a stranger moving at the same enhanced pace. 
Results show that friend-modelled social interactive feedforward improves performance and intrinsic motivation the most.
This indicates that the mere association of the enhanced model with their friend results in a rapid improvement in performance and motivation which implies that social feedforward was successfully elicited by using an enhanced friend's model. 
This widens the application of self-modelled feedforward to a wide range of social options which enables players to also reap the benefits of socialising in addition to feedforward benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barathi, S. C., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Proulx, M. J., O'Neill, E., Lutteroth, C.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Advantages of Friend-Modelled Social Interactive Feedforward for VR Exergaming&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
ACM CHI PLAY 2024&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3677103"&gt;DOI:10.1145/3677103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="vr"></category><category term="virtual reality"></category><category term="exergaming"></category><category term="social interactive feedforward"></category><category term="performance"></category><category term="extrinsic motivation"></category><category term="paper"></category></entry><entry><title>New paper accepted in Journal of Obsessive-Compulsive and Related Disorders!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/vr-ocd-2024.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T11:22:31+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2024-07-04:/vr-ocd-2024.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Journal of Obsessive-Compulsive and Related Disorders&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended reality (XR) technologies including virtual and augmented reality are seeing increasing research interest in the field of mental health. 
Obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD) is a condition that remains difficult to assess and treat despite …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Journal of Obsessive-Compulsive and Related Disorders&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended reality (XR) technologies including virtual and augmented reality are seeing increasing research interest in the field of mental health. 
Obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD) is a condition that remains difficult to assess and treat despite the availability of effective therapies. 
This systematic review synthesises the current knowledge regarding the use and effectiveness of XR in the assessment, treatment, and study of OCD. 
The protocol for this review was registered on PROSPERO (ID: CRD42021248021). Searches of six databases were conducted. 
The xReality framework was used to define which technologies would be included as XR. 
Studies that recruited analogue samples as well as clinical OCD populations were included. 
A narrative synthesis of the findings was planned. 
There was consistent evidence for the use of virtual reality as a tool for symptom provocation in people with contamination-related OCD, as part of exposure and response prevention. 
Significant heterogeneity exists between study designs found in both symptom provocation and treatment outcome studies. 
This review has important implications about the narrow focus of research in this area thus far, highlighting the need for further study of different uses of XR in providing positive treatment outcomes across a broader range of OCD symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colman, M., Millar, J., Patil, B., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Russell, A., Higson-Sweeney, N., Aguiar, M., Stanton Fraser., D.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A systematic review and narrative synthesis of the use and effectiveness of extended reality technology in the assessment, treatment and study of obsessive compulsive disorder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Journal of Obsessive-Compulsive and Related Disorders.&lt;br&gt;
DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocrd.2024.100893"&gt;10.1016/j.jocrd.2024.100893&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="vr"></category><category term="virtual reality"></category><category term="ocd"></category><category term="review"></category><category term="obsessive compulsive disorder"></category><category term="xr"></category><category term="paper"></category></entry><entry><title>New paper accepted in Experimental Brain Research!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/vr_motion_sickness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T11:21:49+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2023-12-01:/vr_motion_sickness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Experimental Brain Research&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual reality (VR) technology has been widely adopted for several professional and recreational applications. Despite rapid innovation in hardware and software, one of the long prevailing issues for end users of VR is the experience of VR sickness …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Experimental Brain Research&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual reality (VR) technology has been widely adopted for several professional and recreational applications. Despite rapid innovation in hardware and software, one of the long prevailing issues for end users of VR is the experience of VR sickness. 
Females experience stronger VR sickness compared to males, and previous research has linked susceptibility to VR sickness to the menstrual cycle (Munafo, Diedrick, &amp;amp; Stoffregen, 2017). 
Here we investigated the female versus male experience in VR sickness while playing an immersive VR game, comparing days of the menstrual cycle when hormones peak: day 15 (ovulation - peak oestrogen) and day 22 (mid-luteal phase - peak progesterone).
We found that immersion duration was greater in the second session than the first, and discomfort was lessened, suggesting a powerful adaptation with repeated exposure.
Due to the oestrogen levels changing along with the exposure, there was no clear independent impact of that; note, though, that there was a significant difference between self-report and physiological measures implying that GSR is potentially an unreliable measure of motion sickness.
Although prior work found a delay over two days between session would not allow adaptation and habituation to reduce VR sickness susceptibility, we found that a week delay has potential success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bannigan, G. M., de Sousa, A., Scheller, M., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.&lt;/b&gt;, Proulx, M. J.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Potential factors contributing to observed sex differences in Virtual Reality induced sickness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Experimental Brain Research.&lt;br&gt;
DOI: &lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00221-023-06760-0"&gt;10.1007/s00221-023-06760-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="vr"></category><category term="virtual reality"></category><category term="motion sickness"></category><category term="menstrual cycle"></category><category term="psychophysiology"></category><category term="paper"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication in Gerontology and Geriatric Medicine!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/virtual-reality-tackling-loneliness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-12-21T11:26:03+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2023-06-20:/virtual-reality-tackling-loneliness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Gerontology and Geriatric Medicine&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current trends in gerontology conceptualize Virtual Reality (VR) as a tool for rehabilitation, lauding its potential for cognitive rehabilitation or as an intervention to reduce cognitive function decline (D'Cunha, et al., 2019) (Bauer &amp;amp; Andringa, 2020) (Sayma, Tuijt …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Gerontology and Geriatric Medicine&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current trends in gerontology conceptualize Virtual Reality (VR) as a tool for rehabilitation, lauding its potential for cognitive rehabilitation or as an intervention to reduce cognitive function decline (D'Cunha, et al., 2019) (Bauer &amp;amp; Andringa, 2020) (Sayma, Tuijt, Cooper, &amp;amp; Walters, 2020) (Moyle, Jones, Dwan, &amp;amp; Petrovich, 2018). 
However, we must take a critical stance and identify not just the potential positive impact, but also how things may go wrong without appropriate guidelines, and the need for careful design around the interaction affordances of the technology.
We conducted co-discovery and co-design workshops involving expert stakeholders and older adults (N=20) over a period of 6 month, involving practical activities including user personas and focus groups to understand the complexities of loneliness and identify possible solutions with VR.
Based on our findings we focus our argument on two key factors in the conceptualization of loneliness: spaces, and activities which may take place within said spaces. 
We present our reconceptualization of VR as a tool for group activities instead of passive consumption of content and make a first step suggestions to the community for reducing feelings of loneliness with VR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Campbell, S.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tackling Loneliness and Isolation in older adults with Virtual Reality: How do we move forward?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Gerontology and Geriatric Medicine.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1177/23337214231186204"&gt;DOI: 10.1177/23337214231186204&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/epdf/10.1177/23337214231186204"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="gerontology"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="ethics"></category><category term="virtual reality"></category><category term="mixed reality"></category><category term="augmented reality"></category><category term="perspective"></category><category term="loneliness"></category></entry><entry><title>New Paper in ACM TAP!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/tap-aug-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T14:57:44+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2021-08-24:/tap-aug-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted into TAP!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasonic mid-air haptic technologies, which provide haptic feedback through airwaves produced using ultrasound, could be
employed to investigate the sense of body ownership and immersion in virtual reality (VR) by inducing the virtual hand illusion (VHI).
Ultrasonic mid-air haptic perception …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted into TAP!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasonic mid-air haptic technologies, which provide haptic feedback through airwaves produced using ultrasound, could be
employed to investigate the sense of body ownership and immersion in virtual reality (VR) by inducing the virtual hand illusion (VHI).
Ultrasonic mid-air haptic perception has solely been investigated for glabrous (hairless) skin, which has higher tactile sensitivity than hairy skin.
In contrast, the VHI paradigm typically targets hairy skin without comparisons to glabrous skin.
The aim of this paper was to investigate illusory body ownership, the applicability of ultrasonic mid-air haptics, and perceived immersion in VR using the VHI.
Fifty participants viewed a virtual hand being stroked by a feather synchronously and asynchronously with the ultrasonic stimulation applied to the glabrous skin on the palmar surface and the hairy skin on the dorsal surface of their hands.
Questionnaire responses revealed that synchronous stimulation induced a stronger VHI than asynchronous stimulation.
In synchronous conditions, the VHI was stronger for palmar stimulation than dorsal stimulation.
The ultrasonic stimulation was also perceived as more intense on the palmar surface compared to the dorsal surface.
Perceived immersion was not related to illusory body ownership per se but was enhanced by the provision of synchronous stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salagean, A., Hadnett-Hunter, J. E., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; de Sousa, A., Proulx, M.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A Virtual Reality Application of the Rubber Hand Illusion Induced by Ultrasonic Mid-Air Haptic Stimulation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
ACM Transactions on Applied Perception&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://orca.cardiff.ac.uk/143639"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3487563"&gt;DOI: 10.1145/3487563&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="rubber hand illusion"></category><category term="ultraleap"></category><category term="ultrahaptics"></category><category term="perception"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication in Frontiers in Virtual Reality!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/cassandra-complex.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T12:28:53+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2021-05-05:/cassandra-complex.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Virtual Reality&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent years have seen a boom in Virtual, Augmented, and Mixed Reality technologies which have been widely adopted both by the consumer market and the research community. 
These technologies have provided researchers the ability to generate and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Virtual Reality&lt;/i&gt;! Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent years have seen a boom in Virtual, Augmented, and Mixed Reality technologies which have been widely adopted both by the consumer market and the research community. 
These technologies have provided researchers the ability to generate and gather data in new ways, through world building and scenario creation in every environment imagined. 
Although this growing interest is exciting, there is also a mounting concern about best practises and ethical dilemmas. 
In the literature one can already find a large quantity of papers providing guidelines and raising ethical concerns. 
However, ethical pitfalls continue to be overlooked. 
In this opinion paper, prompted by the ethics developments in Artificial Intelligence (AI), another area with rapid growth and adoption which has been overwhelmed by a huge number of guidelines and is still nowhere close to universal acceptance of standards, we propose that the virtual, augmented, and mixed reality research and development areas need to come together as whole; involving government, industry and science in order to define, develop and decide guidelines and strategies before we replicate the devastating consequences such as decaying trust in technology witnessed in other areas like social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Zoumpoulaki, A., Eslambolchilar, P.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Does Mixed Reality Have a Cassandra Complex?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Frontiers in Virtual Reality--Virtual Reality and Human Behaviour.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.3389/frvir.2021.673547"&gt;DOI: 10.3389/frvir.2021.673547&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="frontiers"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="ethics"></category><category term="virtual reality"></category><category term="mixed reality"></category><category term="augmented reality"></category><category term="opinion"></category></entry><entry><title>New Paper at INTERACT 2021!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/interact-aug-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T12:28:53+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2021-04-03:/interact-aug-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted into INTERACT 2021!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility in sports media broadcast (SMB) remains a problem for blind spectators who wish to socialize and watch sports with friends and family.
Although popular, radio's reliance on low bandwidth speech results in an overwhelming experience for blind spectators …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted into INTERACT 2021!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility in sports media broadcast (SMB) remains a problem for blind spectators who wish to socialize and watch sports with friends and family.
Although popular, radio's reliance on low bandwidth speech results in an overwhelming experience for blind spectators.
In this paper we focused on two core issues: (i) how SMB can be augmented to convey diegetic information more effectively, and (ii) the social context in which SMB are consumed.
We chose tennis broadcasts for our investigations.
Addressing issue (i), we developed a system design and prototype to enhance the experience of watching tennis matches, focusing on blind spectators using audio descriptions and 3D audio, and evaluated our system with (n=12) in a controlled user evaluation.
Our results indicate how audio descriptions gave clear information for the tennis ball placements, 3D audio provided subtle cues for the ball direction, and radio provided desired human commentary.
For issue (ii), we conducted an online questionnaire (n=15) investigating the social context in which blind spectators consume SMB. 
Participant feedback indicated there is a demand for more accessible SMB content such that people can consume SMB by themselves and with their friends.
Participants were enthusiastic for a revised system design mixing elements from 3D audio and audio description.
We discuss our results in the context of social SMB spectatorship, concluding with insights into accessible SMB technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goncu, C., &amp;amp; &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Did you see that!?' Enhancing the Experience of Sports Media Broadcast for Blind People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
International Federation for Information Processing Technical Committee on Human Computer Interaction (IFIP TC13) Bi-annual International Conference (INTERACT)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-85623-6_24"&gt;DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-85623-6_24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category><category term="ifip tc13"></category><category term="spectatorship"></category><category term="tennis"></category><category term="accessibility"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication in ACM Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/agonistic-games.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T14:57:44+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2020-11-12:/agonistic-games.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in the ACM Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage special issue on Culture Games!
This paper is an analysis of 2 games we made as part of the EU Horizon 2020 UNREST project.
We &lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chiplay-2018.html"&gt;previously wrote&lt;/a&gt; (descriptively) about the games, but this paper is a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in the ACM Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage special issue on Culture Games!
This paper is an analysis of 2 games we made as part of the EU Horizon 2020 UNREST project.
We &lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chiplay-2018.html"&gt;previously wrote&lt;/a&gt; (descriptively) about the games, but this paper is a comprehensive study on our installation at the Ruhr Museum, considering reactions from museum visitors and the like.
To the best of our knowledge, this paper is the first to discuss what we define as Agonistic Games: serious games which explore the theme of agonism.
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose Agonistic Games (AGs) as a serious games subcategory that can stimulate critical reflection on topics of dark heritage through multiperspectivity and unsettling play.
We first discuss the emerging topic of agonism in memory studies, and then how games can be used to support its objectives.
We then discuss the development of 2 original AGs: Endless Blitz and Umschlagplatz '43. 
We explore whether these two AGs were perceived as capable of stimulating critical reflection by collecting data from visitors to the exhibition 'Krieg. Macht. Sinn' at the Ruhr Museum in Germany where the games were installed, and from participants in an online course describing the games.
From analysing data collected, we outline four factors inhibiting the capacity of AGs to stimulate critical reflection (topic, context, design, and assumptions about games) and propose strategies for overcoming these inhibitors. 
Our findings are valuable to scholars, game researchers, and designers, strengthening the foundations for the design and development of future AGs.investigation to inform the design of effective remote-learning applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Angeli, &lt;b&gt;D., Finnegan,&lt;/b&gt; D.J., Scott, L., O'Neill, E.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Unsettling Play: Perceptions of Agonistic Games&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
ACM Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage Special Issue on Culture Games.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3431925"&gt;DOI: 10.1145/3431925&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://orca.cardiff.ac.uk/136295/"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="games"></category><category term="culture"></category><category term="heritage"></category><category term="agonism"></category><category term="endless blitz"></category><category term="umschlagplatz '43"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication in PeerJ Computer Science!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/immersive-vles-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T14:57:44+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2020-10-22:/immersive-vles-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in the PeerJ Open Access journal for Computer Science!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massive Open Online Courses are a dominant force in remote-learning yet suffer from persisting problems stemming from lack of commitment and low completion rates. 
In this initial study we investigate how the use …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted in the PeerJ Open Access journal for Computer Science!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massive Open Online Courses are a dominant force in remote-learning yet suffer from persisting problems stemming from lack of commitment and low completion rates. 
In this initial study we investigate how the use of immersive virtual environments for Power-Point based informational learning may benefit learners and mimic traditional lectures successfully. 
We examine the role of embodied agent tutors which are frequently implemented within virtual learning environments. 
We find similar performance on a bespoke knowledge test and metrics for motivation, satisfaction, and engagement by learners in both real and virtual environments, regardless of embodied agent tutor presence. 
Our results raise questions regarding the viability of using virtual environments for remote-learning paradigms, and we emphasise  the need for further investigation to inform the design of effective remote-learning applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitton, I. S., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Proulx, M. J.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Immersive virtual environments and embodied agents for e-learning applications&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
PeerJ Open Access Computer Science&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.315"&gt;DOI: 10.7717/peerj-cs.315&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://orca.cardiff.ac.uk/135879/"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="peerj"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="immersive virtual environments"></category><category term="elearning"></category><category term="vr"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication @ IDC 2020!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/inclusive-pd-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T12:28:53+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2020-05-30:/inclusive-pd-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted to the &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/worldsmostinclusivepdproject/home"&gt;World's Most Inclusive Participatory Design Workshop&lt;/a&gt; @ the ACM Interaction Design &amp;amp; Children conference!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game Jams are planned events in which attendees engage in practices of co-creation in an attempt to devise a game concept and prototype. 
They are designed to be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted to the &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/worldsmostinclusivepdproject/home"&gt;World's Most Inclusive Participatory Design Workshop&lt;/a&gt; @ the ACM Interaction Design &amp;amp; Children conference!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game Jams are planned events in which attendees engage in practices of co-creation in an attempt to devise a game concept and prototype. 
They are designed to be fun, participatory, and stimulate creativity over a short intense period of time.
We report on a recent Game Jam, &lt;em&gt;Sacred Spring&lt;/em&gt;, aimed at educating children on the medical and scientific history of the Roman Baths in the city of Bath, UK.
In this paper, we describe the event and its output, with some brief discussion on what we learned from organizing and running the game jam with a group of children aged 6-9 years old.
Our aim is to discuss our Game Jam with the inclusive participatory design (PD) community, contextualizing novel game design and game play based learning strategies in the PD space, and devising ways to reach a broader audience in future workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague &lt;a href="https://www.danieladeangeli.com/"&gt;Dr Daniela De Angeli&lt;/a&gt; is attending and representing our work.
No video this time, but I'll update this post with images from the workshop when I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Angeli, &lt;b&gt;D., Finnegan,&lt;/b&gt; D. J., Scott, L.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sacred Springs&lt;/em&gt;: Teaching Children Local History via a Game Jam.&lt;br&gt;
In: Constantin, A., Korte, J.,Wilson, C., Alexandru, C.A., Good, J., Sim, G., Read, J., Fails, J.A., Eriksson, E. (Eds.), Planning the World's Most Inclusive PD Project, ACM Interaction Design and Children (IDC) conference 2020.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/game-jam-inclusive-pd-2020.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="workshop proceedings"></category><category term="participatory design"></category><category term="games"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication @ CHI PLAY 2018!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chiplay-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-05-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2018-09-03:/chiplay-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a publication accepted at CHI PLAY 2018!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historical narratives of conflict typically revolve around heroes and villains or perpetrators and victims.
However, this dichotomy of events and people into good and evil greatly reduces the extent to which the past can be analysed, explained, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a publication accepted at CHI PLAY 2018!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historical narratives of conflict typically revolve around heroes and villains or perpetrators and victims.
However, this dichotomy of events and people into good and evil greatly reduces the extent to which the past can be analysed, explained, and understood.
To truly understand the actions that lead to conflict, one must appreciate the dense network of relationships between social agents, each with their own personal motivations and ideals.
A contemporary political viewpoint capturing this multiperspectivity is that of Agonism.
Focusing on the characters and events, Agonism emphasises the socio-cultural interactions and relationships between all agents involved including bystanders and, crucially, perpetrators. 
We discuss two 'Games for a Social Change' that we have developed to promote an Agonistic view: &lt;em&gt;Endless Blitz&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Umschlag '43&lt;/em&gt;.
We describe the games themselves, and the framework of memory studies that informs our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a demo reel of both Endless Blitz and Umschlagplatz '43 in action!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [![Endless Blitz](https://i.imgur.com/hr70Dge.png)](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1EODVqZ7YuxX5pWay5lDQEH2uxsR_aWei/view?usp=sharing "Endless Blitz") --&gt;

&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9YT1if8fZ9Y" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Angeli, &lt;b&gt;D., Finnegan,&lt;/b&gt; D. J., Scott, L., Bull, A., O'Neill, E.&lt;br&gt;
Agonistic Games: Multiperspective and Unsettling Games for a Social Change.&lt;br&gt;
CHI PLAY '18 Extended Abstracts.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3270316.3270594"&gt;DOI: 10.1145/3270316.3270594&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/chiplay-2018.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category><category term="agonism"></category><category term="games"></category><category term="chiplay"></category><category term="endless blitz"></category><category term="umschlagplatz '43"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication @ ECCV 2018!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/eccv-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-07-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2018-07-26:/eccv-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a publication accepted at ECCV 2018!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work presents a novel hand pose estimation framework via intermediate dense guidance map supervision. 
By leveraging the advantage of predicting heat maps of hand joints in detection-based methods, we propose to use dense feature maps through intermediate supervision …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a publication accepted at ECCV 2018!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work presents a novel hand pose estimation framework via intermediate dense guidance map supervision. 
By leveraging the advantage of predicting heat maps of hand joints in detection-based methods, we propose to use dense feature maps through intermediate supervision in a regression-based framework that is not limited to the resolution of the heat map. 
Our dense feature maps are delicately designed to encode the hand geometry and the spatial relation between local joint and global hand. 
The proposed framework significantly improves the state-of-the-art in both 2D and 3D on the recent benchmark datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://xkunwu.github.io/"&gt;Xiaokun Wu&lt;/a&gt; wrote up an awesome post on the project on his &lt;a href="https://xkunwu.github.io/research/18HandPose/18HandPose"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.
I recommend reading it!
They say pictures speak a thousand words, so here's a gif Xiaokun made giving the general idea in a succint way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://xkunwu.github.io/projects/hand-track/test_seq.gif" alt="gif of hand tracking software" /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, X., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; O'Neill, E., Yang, Y.&lt;br&gt;
HandMap: Robust Hand Pose Estimation via Intermediate Dense Guidance Map Supervision.&lt;br&gt;
ECCV 2018: Proceedings of the 15th European Conference on Computer Vision.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-01270-0_15"&gt;DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-01270-0_15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/eccv-2018.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="ieee"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category><category term="computer vision"></category><category term="hand tracking"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication @ CHI 2018!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chi-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2018-02-16:/chi-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted at CHI 2018!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big challenges today is to keep people healthy through sufficient exercise. 
In this project we developed a new method for improving exercise performance in a motivating manner using a VR exergame.
Players can work out on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've had a paper accepted at CHI 2018!
Here's the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big challenges today is to keep people healthy through sufficient exercise. 
In this project we developed a new method for improving exercise performance in a motivating manner using a VR exergame.
Players can work out on an exercycle doing high-intensity interval training while wearing a VR headset and racing in a virtual world. 
Our method is an interactive adaptation of Feedforward, a type of training used to achieve rapid improvements by creating self models showing previously unachieved performance levels. 
The game lets players compete against themselves, making it a bit harder for them so they are able to surpass their own previous performance. 
Our method helped players perform better and also have a better experience compared to racing against a virtual competitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a video of the work, and you can follow the the &lt;a href="https://www.bath.ac.uk/research-centres/reality-and-virtual-environments-augmentation-labs-reveal/"&gt;ReVEaL&lt;/a&gt; to see more about what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7T4bdlRDOdk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barathi, S. C., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Farrow, M., Whaley, A., Heath, P., Buckley, J., Dowrick, P. W., Wünsche, B. C., Bilzon, J. L. J., O'Neill, E. &amp;amp; Lutteroth, C.&lt;br&gt;
Interactive Feedforward for Improving Performance and Maintaining Intrinsic Motivation in VR Exergaming.&lt;br&gt;
CHI 18': Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173982"&gt;DOI: 10.1145/3173574.3173982&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/chi-2018.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category><category term="exergame"></category><category term="games"></category></entry><entry><title>New paper accepted into SIVE 2017!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/sive-ieeevr-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2017-02-28:/sive-ieeevr-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My paper titled "An Approach to Reducing Distance Compression in Audiovisual Virtual Environments" has been accepted into the &lt;a href="http://imi.aau.dk/~sts/SIVE17/"&gt;SIVE (Sonic Interactions in Virtual Environments)&lt;/a&gt; workshop as part of &lt;a href="http://ieeevr.org/2017/"&gt;IEEE VR 2017&lt;/a&gt;!
I will be presenting my paper and it will be published as part of the conference proceedings.
See you …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My paper titled "An Approach to Reducing Distance Compression in Audiovisual Virtual Environments" has been accepted into the &lt;a href="http://imi.aau.dk/~sts/SIVE17/"&gt;SIVE (Sonic Interactions in Virtual Environments)&lt;/a&gt; workshop as part of &lt;a href="http://ieeevr.org/2017/"&gt;IEEE VR 2017&lt;/a&gt;!
I will be presenting my paper and it will be published as part of the conference proceedings.
See you in LA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; O'Neill, E., &amp;amp; Proulx, M. J.&lt;br&gt;
An approach to reducing distance compression in audiovisual virtual environments.&lt;br&gt;
In Sonic Interactions for Virtual Environments (SIVE), 2017 IEEE 3rd VR Workshop on (pp. 1-6). IEEE.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/SIVE.2017.7901607"&gt;DOI: 10.1109/SIVE.2017.7901607&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/sive-2017.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="ieee"></category><category term="VR"></category><category term="binaural"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category></entry></feed>