<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>"There's always money in the banana stand!" - Papers</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/feeds/papers.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ps2fino.github.io/</id><updated>2021-09-28T15:34:54+02:00</updated><entry><title>New Paper in ACM TAP!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/tap-aug-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-28T15:34:54+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2021-08-24:/tap-aug-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted into &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TAP&lt;/span&gt;!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasonic mid-air haptic technologies, which provide haptic feedback through airwaves produced using ultrasound, could be
employed to investigate the sense of body ownership and immersion in virtual reality (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt;) by inducing the virtual hand illusion (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHI&lt;/span&gt;).
Ultrasonic mid-air …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted into &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TAP&lt;/span&gt;!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasonic mid-air haptic technologies, which provide haptic feedback through airwaves produced using ultrasound, could be
employed to investigate the sense of body ownership and immersion in virtual reality (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt;) by inducing the virtual hand illusion (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHI&lt;/span&gt;).
Ultrasonic mid-air haptic perception has solely been investigated for glabrous (hairless) skin, which has higher tactile sensitivity than hairy skin.
In contrast, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHI&lt;/span&gt; paradigm typically targets hairy skin without comparisons to glabrous skin.
The aim of this paper was to investigate illusory body ownership, the applicability of ultrasonic mid-air haptics, and perceived immersion in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; using the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHI&lt;/span&gt;.
Fifty participants viewed a virtual hand being stroked by a feather synchronously and asynchronously with the ultrasonic stimulation applied to the glabrous skin on the palmar surface and the hairy skin on the dorsal surface of their hands.
Questionnaire responses revealed that synchronous stimulation induced a stronger &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHI&lt;/span&gt; than asynchronous stimulation.
In synchronous conditions, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHI&lt;/span&gt; was stronger for palmar stimulation than dorsal stimulation.
The ultrasonic stimulation was also perceived as more intense on the palmar surface compared to the dorsal surface.
Perceived immersion was not related to illusory body ownership per se but was enhanced by the provision of synchronous&amp;nbsp;stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salagean, A., Hadnett-Hunter, J. E., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; de Sousa, A., Proulx, M.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A Virtual Reality Application of the Rubber Hand Illusion Induced by Ultrasonic Mid-Air Haptic Stimulation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; Transactions on Applied Perception&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://orca.cf.ac.uk/143639"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="rubber hand illusion"></category><category term="ultraleap"></category><category term="ultrahaptics"></category><category term="perception"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication in Frontiers in Virtual Reality!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/cassandra-complex.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-28T15:34:54+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2021-05-05:/cassandra-complex.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Virtual Reality&lt;/i&gt;! Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent years have seen a boom in Virtual, Augmented, and Mixed Reality technologies which have been widely adopted both by the consumer market and the research community. 
These technologies have provided researchers the ability to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Virtual Reality&lt;/i&gt;! Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent years have seen a boom in Virtual, Augmented, and Mixed Reality technologies which have been widely adopted both by the consumer market and the research community. 
These technologies have provided researchers the ability to generate and gather data in new ways, through world building and scenario creation in every environment imagined. 
Although this growing interest is exciting, there is also a mounting concern about best practises and ethical dilemmas. 
In the literature one can already find a large quantity of papers providing guidelines and raising ethical concerns. 
However, ethical pitfalls continue to be overlooked. 
In this opinion paper, prompted by the ethics developments in Artificial Intelligence (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AI&lt;/span&gt;), another area with rapid growth and adoption which has been overwhelmed by a huge number of guidelines and is still nowhere close to universal acceptance of standards, we propose that the virtual, augmented, and mixed reality research and development areas need to come together as whole; involving government, industry and science in order to define, develop and decide guidelines and strategies before we replicate the devastating consequences such as decaying trust in technology witnessed in other areas like social&amp;nbsp;media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Zoumpoulaki, A., Eslambolchilar, P.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Does Mixed Reality Have a Cassandra Complex?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Frontiers in Virtual Reality&amp;#8212;Virtual Reality and Human Behaviour.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.3389/frvir.2021.673547"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOI&lt;/span&gt;:&amp;nbsp;10.3389/frvir.2021.673547&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="frontiers"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="ethics"></category><category term="virtual reality"></category><category term="mixed reality"></category><category term="augmented reality"></category><category term="opinion"></category></entry><entry><title>New Paper at INTERACT 2021!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/interact-aug-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-28T15:34:54+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2021-04-03:/interact-aug-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted into &lt;span class="caps"&gt;INTERACT&lt;/span&gt; 2021!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility in sports media broadcast (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt;) remains a problem for blind spectators who wish to socialize and watch sports with friends and family.
Although popular, radio&amp;#8217;s reliance on low bandwidth speech results in an overwhelming experience …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted into &lt;span class="caps"&gt;INTERACT&lt;/span&gt; 2021!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility in sports media broadcast (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt;) remains a problem for blind spectators who wish to socialize and watch sports with friends and family.
Although popular, radio&amp;#8217;s reliance on low bandwidth speech results in an overwhelming experience for blind spectators.
In this paper we focused on two core issues: (i) how &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt; can be augmented to convey diegetic information more effectively, and (ii) the social context in which &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt; are consumed.
We chose tennis broadcasts for our investigations.
Addressing issue (i), we developed a system design and prototype to enhance the experience of watching tennis matches, focusing on blind spectators using audio descriptions and 3D audio, and evaluated our system with (n=12) in a controlled user evaluation.
Our results indicate how audio descriptions gave clear information for the tennis ball placements, 3D audio provided subtle cues for the ball direction, and radio provided desired human commentary.
For issue (ii), we conducted an online questionnaire (n=15) investigating the social context in which blind spectators consume &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt;. 
Participant feedback indicated there is a demand for more accessible &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt; content such that people can consume &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt; by themselves and with their friends.
Participants were enthusiastic for a revised system design mixing elements from 3D audio and audio description.
We discuss our results in the context of social &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt; spectatorship, concluding with insights into accessible &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMB&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goncu, C., &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;D. J.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Did you see that!?&amp;#8217; Enhancing the Experience of Sports Media Broadcast for Blind People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
International Federation for Information Processing Technical Committee on Human Computer Interaction (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IFIP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TC13&lt;/span&gt;) Bi-annual International Conference (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;INTERACT&lt;/span&gt;)  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category><category term="ifip tc13"></category><category term="spectatorship"></category><category term="tennis"></category><category term="accessibility"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication in ACM Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/agonistic-games.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-09-28T15:34:54+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2020-11-12:/agonistic-games.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage special issue on Culture Games!
This paper is an analysis of 2 games we made as part of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; Horizon 2020 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNREST&lt;/span&gt; project.
We &lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chiplay-2018.html"&gt;previously wrote&lt;/a&gt; (descriptively) about the games, but this paper is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage special issue on Culture Games!
This paper is an analysis of 2 games we made as part of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; Horizon 2020 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNREST&lt;/span&gt; project.
We &lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chiplay-2018.html"&gt;previously wrote&lt;/a&gt; (descriptively) about the games, but this paper is a comprehensive study on our installation at the Ruhr Museum, considering reactions from museum visitors and the like.
To the best of our knowledge, this paper is the first to discuss what we define as Agonistic Games: serious games which explore the theme of agonism.
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose Agonistic Games (AGs) as a serious games subcategory that can stimulate critical reflection on topics of dark heritage through multiperspectivity and unsettling play.
We first discuss the emerging topic of agonism in memory studies, and then how games can be used to support its objectives.
We then discuss the development of 2 original AGs: Endless Blitz and Umschlagplatz &amp;#8216;43. 
We explore whether these two AGs were perceived as capable of stimulating critical reflection by collecting data from visitors to the exhibition &amp;#8216;Krieg. Macht. Sinn&amp;#8217; at the Ruhr Museum in Germany where the games were installed, and from participants in an online course describing the games.
From analysing data collected, we outline four factors inhibiting the capacity of AGs to stimulate critical reflection (topic, context, design, and assumptions about games) and propose strategies for overcoming these inhibitors. 
Our findings are valuable to scholars, game researchers, and designers, strengthening the foundations for the design and development of future AGs.investigation to inform the design of effective remote-learning&amp;nbsp;applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Angeli, &lt;b&gt;D., Finnegan,&lt;/b&gt; D.J., Scott, L., O&amp;#8217;Neill, E.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Unsettling Play: Perceptions of Agonistic Games&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage Special Issue on Culture Games.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3431925"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOI&lt;/span&gt;: 10.1145/3431925&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://orca.cf.ac.uk/136295/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="games"></category><category term="culture"></category><category term="heritage"></category><category term="agonism"></category><category term="endless blitz"></category><category term="umschlagplatz '43"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication in PeerJ Computer Science!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/immersive-vles-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-28T15:34:54+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2020-10-22:/immersive-vles-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted in the PeerJ Open Access journal for Computer Science!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massive Open Online Courses are a dominant force in remote-learning yet suffer from persisting problems stemming from lack of commitment and low completion rates. 
In this initial study we investigate how …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted in the PeerJ Open Access journal for Computer Science!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massive Open Online Courses are a dominant force in remote-learning yet suffer from persisting problems stemming from lack of commitment and low completion rates. 
In this initial study we investigate how the use of immersive virtual environments for Power-Point based informational learning may benefit learners and mimic traditional lectures successfully. 
We examine the role of embodied agent tutors which are frequently implemented within virtual learning environments. 
We find similar performance on a bespoke knowledge test and metrics for motivation, satisfaction, and engagement by learners in both real and virtual environments, regardless of embodied agent tutor presence. 
Our results raise questions regarding the viability of using virtual environments for remote-learning paradigms, and we emphasise  the need for further investigation to inform the design of effective remote-learning&amp;nbsp;applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitton, I. S., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Proulx, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;M. J.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Immersive virtual environments and embodied agents for e-learning applications&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
PeerJ Open Access Computer Science&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.315"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOI&lt;/span&gt;: 10.7717/peerj-cs.315&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://orca.cf.ac.uk/135879/1/immersive-vles-2020.pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="peerj"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="immersive virtual environments"></category><category term="elearning"></category><category term="vr"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication @ IDC 2020!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/inclusive-pd-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-28T15:34:54+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2020-05-30:/inclusive-pd-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted to the &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/worldsmostinclusivepdproject/home"&gt;World&amp;#8217;s Most Inclusive Participatory Design Workshop&lt;/a&gt; @ the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; Interaction Design &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Children conference!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game Jams are planned events in which attendees engage in practices of co-creation in an attempt to devise a game concept and prototype. 
They are …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted to the &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/worldsmostinclusivepdproject/home"&gt;World&amp;#8217;s Most Inclusive Participatory Design Workshop&lt;/a&gt; @ the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; Interaction Design &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Children conference!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game Jams are planned events in which attendees engage in practices of co-creation in an attempt to devise a game concept and prototype. 
They are designed to be fun, participatory, and stimulate creativity over a short intense period of time.
We report on a recent Game Jam, &lt;em&gt;Sacred Spring&lt;/em&gt;, aimed at educating children on the medical and scientific history of the Roman Baths in the city of Bath, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt;.
In this paper, we describe the event and its output, with some brief discussion on what we learned from organizing and running the game jam with a group of children aged 6-9 years old.
Our aim is to discuss our Game Jam with the inclusive participatory design (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PD&lt;/span&gt;) community, contextualizing novel game design and game play based learning strategies in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PD&lt;/span&gt; space, and devising ways to reach a broader audience in future&amp;nbsp;workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague &lt;a href="https://www.danieladeangeli.com/"&gt;Dr Daniela De Angeli&lt;/a&gt; is attending and representing our work.
No video this time, but I&amp;#8217;ll update this post with images from the workshop when I&amp;nbsp;can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Angeli, &lt;b&gt;D., Finnegan,&lt;/b&gt; D. J., Scott, L.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sacred Springs&lt;/em&gt;: Teaching Children Local History via a Game Jam.&lt;br&gt;
In: Constantin, A., Korte, J.,Wilson, C., Alexandru, C.A., Good, J., Sim, G., Read, J., Fails, J.A., Eriksson, E. (Eds.), Planning the World&amp;#8217;s Most Inclusive &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PD&lt;/span&gt; Project, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; Interaction Design and Children (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDC&lt;/span&gt;) conference 2020.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/game-jam-inclusive-pd-2020.pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="workshop proceedings"></category><category term="participatory design"></category><category term="games"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication @ CHI PLAY 2018!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chiplay-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-05-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2018-09-03:/chiplay-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a publication accepted at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CHI&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PLAY&lt;/span&gt; 2018!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historical narratives of conflict typically revolve around heroes and villains or perpetrators and victims.
However, this dichotomy of events and people into good and evil greatly reduces the extent to which the past can be analysed …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a publication accepted at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CHI&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PLAY&lt;/span&gt; 2018!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historical narratives of conflict typically revolve around heroes and villains or perpetrators and victims.
However, this dichotomy of events and people into good and evil greatly reduces the extent to which the past can be analysed, explained, and understood.
To truly understand the actions that lead to conflict, one must appreciate the dense network of relationships between social agents, each with their own personal motivations and ideals.
A contemporary political viewpoint capturing this multiperspectivity is that of Agonism.
Focusing on the characters and events, Agonism emphasises the socio-cultural interactions and relationships between all agents involved including bystanders and, crucially, perpetrators. 
We discuss two &amp;#8216;Games for a Social Change&amp;#8217; that we have developed to promote an Agonistic view: &lt;em&gt;Endless Blitz&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Umschlag &amp;#8216;43&lt;/em&gt;.
We describe the games themselves, and the framework of memory studies that informs our&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a demo reel of both Endless Blitz and Umschlagplatz &amp;#8216;43 in&amp;nbsp;action!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [![Endless Blitz](https://i.imgur.com/hr70Dge.png)](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1EODVqZ7YuxX5pWay5lDQEH2uxsR_aWei/view?usp=sharing "Endless Blitz") --&gt;

&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9YT1if8fZ9Y" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Angeli, &lt;b&gt;D., Finnegan,&lt;/b&gt; D. J., Scott, L., Bull, A., O&amp;#8217;Neill, E.&lt;br&gt;
Agonistic Games: Multiperspective and Unsettling Games for a Social Change.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CHI&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PLAY&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8216;18 Extended Abstracts.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3270316.3270594"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOI&lt;/span&gt;: 10.1145/3270316.3270594&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/chiplay-2018.pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category><category term="agonism"></category><category term="games"></category><category term="chiplay"></category><category term="endless blitz"></category><category term="umschlagplatz '43"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication @ ECCV 2018!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/eccv-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-07-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2018-07-26:/eccv-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a publication accepted at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECCV&lt;/span&gt; 2018!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work presents a novel hand pose estimation framework via intermediate dense guidance map supervision. 
By leveraging the advantage of predicting heat maps of hand joints in detection-based methods, we propose to use dense feature maps through …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a publication accepted at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECCV&lt;/span&gt; 2018!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work presents a novel hand pose estimation framework via intermediate dense guidance map supervision. 
By leveraging the advantage of predicting heat maps of hand joints in detection-based methods, we propose to use dense feature maps through intermediate supervision in a regression-based framework that is not limited to the resolution of the heat map. 
Our dense feature maps are delicately designed to encode the hand geometry and the spatial relation between local joint and global hand. 
The proposed framework significantly improves the state-of-the-art in both 2D and 3D on the recent benchmark&amp;nbsp;datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://xkunwu.github.io/"&gt;Xiaokun Wu&lt;/a&gt; wrote up an awesome post on the project on his &lt;a href="https://xkunwu.github.io/research/18HandPose/18HandPose"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.
I recommend reading it!
They say pictures speak a thousand words, so here&amp;#8217;s a gif Xiaokun made giving the general idea in a succint&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://xkunwu.github.io/projects/hand-track/test_seq.gif" alt="gif of hand tracking software" /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, X., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; O&amp;#8217;Neill, E., Yang, Y.&lt;br&gt;
HandMap: Robust Hand Pose Estimation via Intermediate Dense Guidance Map Supervision.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECCV&lt;/span&gt; 2018: Proceedings of the 15th European Conference on Computer Vision.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-01270-0_15"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOI&lt;/span&gt;: 10.1007/978-3-030-01270-0_15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/eccv-2018.pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="ieee"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category><category term="computer vision"></category><category term="hand tracking"></category></entry><entry><title>New Publication @ CHI 2018!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/chi-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2018-02-16:/chi-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CHI&lt;/span&gt; 2018!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big challenges today is to keep people healthy through sufficient exercise. 
In this project we developed a new method for improving exercise performance in a motivating manner using a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; exergame.
Players can work …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had a paper accepted at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CHI&lt;/span&gt; 2018!
Here&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big challenges today is to keep people healthy through sufficient exercise. 
In this project we developed a new method for improving exercise performance in a motivating manner using a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; exergame.
Players can work out on an exercycle doing high-intensity interval training while wearing a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; headset and racing in a virtual world. 
Our method is an interactive adaptation of Feedforward, a type of training used to achieve rapid improvements by creating self models showing previously unachieved performance levels. 
The game lets players compete against themselves, making it a bit harder for them so they are able to surpass their own previous performance. 
Our method helped players perform better and also have a better experience compared to racing against a virtual&amp;nbsp;competitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a video of the work, and you can follow the the &lt;a href="https://www.bath.ac.uk/research-centres/reality-and-virtual-environments-augmentation-labs-reveal/"&gt;ReVEaL&lt;/a&gt; to see more about what we&amp;nbsp;do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7T4bdlRDOdk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barathi, S. C., &lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; Farrow, M., Whaley, A., Heath, P., Buckley, J., Dowrick, P. W., Wünsche, B. C., Bilzon, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;J. L.&lt;/span&gt; J., O&amp;#8217;Neill, E. &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Lutteroth, C.&lt;br&gt;
Interactive Feedforward for Improving Performance and Maintaining Intrinsic Motivation in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; Exergaming.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CHI&lt;/span&gt; 18&amp;#8217;: Proceedings of the 2018 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CHI&lt;/span&gt; Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173982"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOI&lt;/span&gt;: 10.1145/3173574.3173982&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/chi-2018.pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="acm"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category><category term="exergame"></category><category term="games"></category></entry><entry><title>New paper accepted into SIVE 2017!</title><link href="https://ps2fino.github.io/sive-ieeevr-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel J. Finnegan</name></author><id>tag:ps2fino.github.io,2017-02-28:/sive-ieeevr-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My paper titled &amp;#8220;An Approach to Reducing Distance Compression in Audiovisual Virtual Environments&amp;#8221; has been accepted into the &lt;a href="http://imi.aau.dk/~sts/SIVE17/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIVE&lt;/span&gt; (Sonic Interactions in Virtual Environments)&lt;/a&gt; workshop as part of &lt;a href="http://ieeevr.org/2017/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IEEE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; 2017&lt;/a&gt;!
I will be presenting my paper and it will be published as part of the conference proceedings.
See you …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My paper titled &amp;#8220;An Approach to Reducing Distance Compression in Audiovisual Virtual Environments&amp;#8221; has been accepted into the &lt;a href="http://imi.aau.dk/~sts/SIVE17/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIVE&lt;/span&gt; (Sonic Interactions in Virtual Environments)&lt;/a&gt; workshop as part of &lt;a href="http://ieeevr.org/2017/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IEEE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; 2017&lt;/a&gt;!
I will be presenting my paper and it will be published as part of the conference proceedings.
See you in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LA&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finnegan, D. J.,&lt;/b&gt; O&amp;#8217;Neill, E., &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Proulx, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;M. J.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
An approach to reducing distance compression in audiovisual virtual environments.&lt;br&gt;
In Sonic Interactions for Virtual Environments (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIVE&lt;/span&gt;), 2017 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IEEE&lt;/span&gt; 3rd &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt; Workshop on (pp. 1-6). &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IEEE&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/SIVE.2017.7901607"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOI&lt;/span&gt;: 10.1109/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIVE&lt;/span&gt;.2017.7901607&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ps2fino.github.io/documents/sive-2017.pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Papers"></category><category term="ieee"></category><category term="VR"></category><category term="binaural"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="conference proceedings"></category></entry></feed>